In this video, we will be talking about
the
photoelectric effect. To understand this,
it's
very helpful to look at how light
interacts
with matter because we find out in this
unit
that light isn't just non-existent and not
matter.
Light is matter. It's made up of tiny
particles
called photons. So let's say we have a
metal
surface over here and we strike a beam of
light
through it. This light may result in some
electrons
being emitted out of the metal atoms.
So in an experiment, you might see some
electrons
being emitted. I've explained that through
here.
Remember when I mentioned that there is an
infinity
energy level and that's when the electron
is
ejected? Some photons have enough energy
to
eject that. But before, when they were
doing
this experiment, we didn't know that. We
just
thought that if we had more photons, if we
increase
the number of photons or the intensity of
the
light, more electrons will be ejected.
And obviously that wasn't the case.
Light, if they kept it at the same
frequency
or kept the photons with the same amount
of
energy, no electrons would be ejected.
Because even if trillions of electrons
bombarded
this, let's say, metal atom, if they don't
have
enough energy to make an electron jump
from
the first energy level all the way to
infinity,
then, well, it's not going to emit an
electron.
And we later realized it from Einstein's
explanation.
And scientists thought that light was only
a
wave. But based off of Einstein's
explanation,
we realized that light is actually matter.
It behaves like photons. And that helped
us
understand a lot of things, such as in
order
to increase the amount of electrons being
emitted
from this metal surface, we are going to
have
to increase the frequency. Because this
corresponds
to energy up, and an increased energy per
photon
will result in more electrons emitted.
And just increasing the number of
electrons
won't work. You actually have to increase
the
energy of these photons for more electrons
to
be emitted. And that's an overview of how
we
actually discovered quantum physics and
how
this experiment led to a whole new unit
and
a whole new sector of physics called
modern
physics. Thank you, and we'll see you in
the
next one. Bye!